I've always wanted a bookshop since I
was like seven or eight cuz I'm a
prolific reader and I read lots and lots
of stuff and I've always read so just
something I've always wanted to do I did
eBay for the beginning I did that for
about seven or eight years and then my
brother started a little shop in Lumbee
of all places he had rented a spot to do
a second-hand store and then he could do
it anymore I'm like oh I could a bay and
have a bookstore right cuz eBay was
paying the bills and doing online stuff
and I'm like oh I'm that I could always
do what I wanted so then I came here and
I've been here for six years and it's
awesome cuz it's a I mean who doesn't
love a store
my name is Charlene duelling and I'm the
owner of expressions of time bookstore
in Vernon BC me and my aunt when I lived
in Vancouver used to do antique shows
and expressions of time covers
everything everything cuz everything is
an expression of time from antiques and
the vintage jewelry that I sell to the
books and everything like that so it's
just stuck with me since about night
1995 or something
vintage jewelry is my expertise I've
been doing that for about 25 years
you do need to have your fingers in many
pies when it comes to having a small
business right because you got a lot of
competition out there a lot of people
online like Amazon chapters that kind of
stuff that you're gonna compete with
them you still have to be able to have
multiple things going on hi I'm Angie
and I've worked at expressions of time
for three years now I really like rings
I have a sick obsession so I like to
remain in this corridor here if anybody
ever comes in like the first thing like
you want to see some rings I really do
enjoy the crystals though too
it's something that I'm interested in in
the crystal healing and Halle mental
healing so I really like being able to
put my knowledge to use within that and
being able to you know help people with
certain issues or challenges that
they're having and trying to resolve
those things my name is Jillian and I
for about six
I love the Tarot section I love being
able to kind of hook someone on to Tarot
I guess is show them the Tarot it's like
showing them like starting at all thanks
for joining
when I first opened up it was just me in
the small little space and then and I
decided I needed to be open six days a
week so I hired one of my friends
daughters part-time to work a Sunday and
then it just kind of grew from there as
it got busier it's not just me I I can
do good customer service but they do
awesome customer service they are
they're exactly like when you came in
they're really friendly they're happy
they're you know that's the key also too
so it's not just me it's a whole family
I'm Kayla and I've worked at the store
for six years after six years there's
been a lot of really memorable moments
when customers come in and you can
recall like things about them and it's
more than just them coming in and asking
about books it's about getting help if
we need it or just getting inspiration
if we need it I can remember almost
every single customers name what kind of
books are interested in so if we get a
new book in I can say oh I think Chris
would like to read this book so the next
time that they come in I can show them
that section and I can recommend that
book for them because I think that's
something that they would be interested
someone who's becoming like one of my
best friends I met in here I sold her a
labradorite ring
and then she was like we need to go 40 I
was like we do it's just easy to just
talk to people because you can talk
about anything you like
there's so much information every round
you
[Music]
I'm a sci-fi fantasy reader so it is
easy to get lost in that a little bit
and I do have a lot of sci-fi fantasy in
here but also I guess a general rule of
thumb for me is it interesting so and
I've broadened my spectrum of
interesting and I'm sure since I first
opened the doors cuz we all have our
ideas about exactly what people read and
don't read crystal-blue south held
relationships in case you need to need
to know about your boyfriend he's giving
it 11th want effect loss of feet world
history biography business is all bite
stuff on the other side cuz that's not
that's boring it's art section molding
gardening back to the land crafting if
you wanna learn how to make your own
leather craft brewing that's actually
been a big thing like the native First
Nations local travel field guide science
mathematics class literature section
that's actually one thing that sells
really well
people are always being ambitious about
in classic literature BC and Canada's
children team preteen my favorite
section all the sci-fi fantasy needs to
have my own personal collection of
sci-fi fantasy but now that I have a
book store I don't leave my own library
[Music]
books aren't a luxury but I think a lot
of people still look at them that way
right as I know I can't spend my money
on a book but hey that is so yeah that's
a bit of a change to you right they have
their play with their phones and spend
all kinds of money on tech but sometimes
the local community is key because if
you can't have people shopping from your
local community you're not gonna last
long as a business with all the
competition out there online I work a
lot more than I ever thought I did first
day right do you think oh I be my own
boss I don't have to work but that's not
true at all you work even harder this is
my store my vision I can you know go
where I want to go try things out or
yeah I just be very very creative I
would never go back to working for
somebody else again ever
if I could help but anyway